This task is again about Petri Nets and this
time we have to model a Petri Net.
And the Petri Net is already partially given
below here, and the description says what
we shall model here in this Petri Net.
And it is a check out with a cashier and a
customer.
So, a queue of customers and the conveyor
belt has space for the goods of two customers,
but at each time only one customer is explicitly
modeled.
So, we have just one customer modeled here
and one cashier, so, the checkout has two
places.
When a customer places goods on the conveyor
belt, they first occupy place one.
Goods in place one will be shifted to place
two.
And finally, the cashier processes the goods
which are in place two.
And the customer and also the cashier can
be either busy or waiting and the cashier
can only process goods if he is waiting and
place two of the conveyor belt is not empty.
And after successfully placing the goods or
processing them, the customer or cashier changes
to the state busy after which they become
waiting again shortly.
And after the customer was busy, the new customer
will become waiting, so, that's what the queue,
in this case, will be.
And there are blanks in the chart so, we have
to fill in the statements and we have to fill
in further arrows.
So, first of all, the customer is waiting
or busy this was mentioned here and this is
also true for the cashier.
So, these states here down below should be
the busy states respectively for the customer
and cashier.
So, one for the customer and one for the cashier.
And for the spaces, we have two states as
well, for both states.
For space one and space two it can be either
empty or full.
So, in this case, space two would be empty
and space one would be full.
So that we have both states for space one
and for space two.
And these places represent states, where
one of them has to be selected at all times,
because a space is either empty or full and
there's no in-between.
And also a cashier’s either waiting or busy
and also the same for customer in space one.
So, that means when the customer for this
place, when the customer is waiting,
it has to become either again waiting or busy,
after whatever is happening here.
So, we have to keep that in mind.
Now when the customer is waiting and space
one is empty, then the customer can place
goods onto space one.
This means that this transition can represent
a state so the space is empty and after the
transition, we expect the state to be full.
And also for the customer, who is waiting
before.
Well, when putting things onto the space,
expect him to be busy.
And then they can become waiting at any time.
So, that is why we have another transition
here.
So, when the customer was busy or is busy,
then he can become waiting again, which means,
in fact, that a new customer is coming for
the customer case.
So when the customer is busy and the space
is full now, so then the customer can step
aside, and
then there is space again.
We can think about how the second space becomes
full.
So the second space basically becomes full
when goods will be shifted from place one
to place two.
So, this transition should probably represent
a state.
This means we have goods in space one, but
we don't have goods in space two
because they can only be shifted if the first
space is empty
because if there are goods in space two, then
they haven't been processed by the cashier.
So, now, we can say, when space one is full
and space two is empty, then we want the goods
to be moved to space two.
That means space one should be empty afterwards,
and space two should be full afterwards.
And then again, we can think about the process
of how space two becomes empty.
So, we have a representation for getting it
full, and we have to think about how to get
it empty again.
And therefore, we need the cashier.
The cashier can only process goods if he is
waiting, and the place two of the conveyor
belt is not empty.
So this means this place should probably
represent this state, so the cashier is
waiting and space two is full.
And then there is written after successfully
placing the goods, the customer changes to
the state busy or processing them.
So this again is also for the cashier, so
when the cashier processes the goods then
he becomes busy.
And of course, when the space is processed,
it becomes empty again so that new goods can
be placed on it.
And after a short waiting time, again, as
it was for the customer, the busy cashier
will also become waiting again and therefore
we have this transition here.
And now we are done with our Petri net.
But as we have some conditions that we know
about this state, we can also check them.
And this is, for instance, finally thinking
about what happens for each transition.
And we could do this as a quality check at
the end and think about what happens for each
transition.
So for this transition here, for instance,
you could check that after we process this
transition, we still have tokens in each column
of this graph, so that the customer still
has the state and the space as well.
So when we process this transition, then tokens
would be going out of waiting and empty but
we would then have tokens in busy and full.
And then again, when we have a token
here, then it could go via this transition
here back to this place.
And this transition can only be active if
there is something within this place here.
So as it is required that we have a token
in this place here, and a token in here because
of these connections here.
So this means it could now process this by
activating this or firing this transition,
which would take those two tokens, move one
here and move one here.
And again, after doing that, he could again
fire this transition, which we already checked
is still just one token in each
column.
So this is what still persists also here.
So we have just one token here and only one.
So there's not zero tokens, it's exact exactly
one token in each column here.
And then finally this transition can only
be fired if there is a token in here.
And when we fire this transition, then we
remove these tokens and place them here, as
the arrows indicate, and then the space becomes
empty but the cashier becomes busy.
So still, it's the same picture, we only have
four tokens within our graph, and we have
exactly four tokens within our graph, so they
just shift.
And then again, this transition does also
nothing harmful, because still, we have just
one token in here, if we fire this transition.
So we have checked also that our graph is
working as expected, in the sense that no
token is additionally added in while executing
the graph, or that a token
gets completely removed.
We could check further interactions between
those but I think you get the picture of what's
going on and how you can check that your Petri
Net is correct.